<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="intro_meetings_title">The A.A. Meeting</string>
    <string name="intro_meetings">\tThere are several types of A.A. meetings available for anyone to attend. Meetings last for one hour and generally follow the same structure;
        opening readings followed by a group discussion, a guest speaker, or a reading and discussion from other A.A. approved literature.
        \n\n\tEach begin with the Serenity Prayer spoken by all (if you choose) followed by a moment of silence; to give thought to those who still suffer from addiction.
        \n\n\tA member of the group will then read aloud the A.A. Preamble giving new members a general idea of what the program is.\n\nFollowing this, another member will read
        an excerpt from The Big Book of A.A. titled How It Works.\n\nA reading of the 12 steps and 12 traditions conclude the opening readings of each meeting.\n\nMost meetings will conclude with the Responsibility Pledge and a closing prayer.\n\n</string>

    <string name="reading1_title">A.A. Preamble</string>
    <string name="reading1">\tAlcoholics Anonymous is a fellowship of men and women who share their experience, strength, and hope with each other that they may solve their common
        problem and help others to recover from alcoholism.\n\n\tThe only requirement for membership is the desire to stop drinking. There are no dues or fees for A.A. membership,
        we are self supporting through our own contributions. A.A. is not allied with any sect, denomination, politics, organization or institution; does not wish to engage in any
        controversy; neither endorses nor opposes any causes. Our primary purpose is to stay sober and help other alcoholics to achieve sobriety.</string>
    <string name="reading1_reference">Unknown</string>

    <string name="reading2_title">How It Works</string>
    <string name="reading2">\tRarely have we seen a person fail who has thoroughly followed our path.Those who do not recover are people who cannot or will not completely
        give themselves to this simple program,usually men and women who are constitutionally incapable of being honest with themselves. There are such unfortunates.They
        are not at fault; they seem to have been born that way.They are naturally incapable of grasping and developing a manner of living which demands rigorous honesty.
        Their chances are less than average. There are those, too, who suffer from grave emotional and mental disorders.But many of them do recover if they have the capacity
        to be honest.\n\tOur stories disclose in a general way what we use to be like, what happened, and what we are like now. If you have decided you want what we have and
        are willing to go to any lengths to get it - then you are ready to take certain steps. At some of these we balked. We thought we could find an easier, softer way.
        But we could not. With all the earnestness at our command, we beg of you to be fearless and thorough from the very start. Some of us have tried to hold on to our old
        ideas and the result was nil until we let go absolutely. Remember that we deal with alcohol - cunning, baffling, powerful! \n\tWithout help it is too much for us.
        But there is one who has all power - that One is God. May you find him now!\n\tHalf-measures availed us nothing. We stood at the turning point. We asked His protection
        and care with complete abandon.\n\tHere are the steps we took, which are suggested as a program of recovery. Many of us exclaimed“what an order! I can\'t go through with it.
        \n\nDo not be discouraged. No one among us has been able to maintain anything like perfect adherence to these principles. We are not Saints. The point is, that we are willing
        to grow along spiritual lines. The principles we had set down are guides to progress. We claim spiritual progress rather than spiritual perfection.\n\tOur description of the
        alcoholic, the chapter to the agnostic, and our personal adventures before and after make clear three pertinent ideas:\n\n\tA. That we were alcoholic and could not manage our
        own lives.\n\tB. That probably no human power could have relieved our alcoholism.\n\tC. That God could and would if he were sought.\n</string>
    <string name="reading2_reference">Unknown</string>

    <string name="reading2a">Rarely have we seen a person fail who has thoroughly followed our path.Those who do not recover are people who cannot or will not completely
                give themselves to this simple program,usually men and women who are constitutionally incapable of being honest with themselves. There are such unfortunates.They
                are not at fault; they seem to have been born that way.They are naturally incapable of grasping and developing a manner of living which demands rigorous honesty.
                Their chances are less than average. There are those, too, who suffer from grave emotional and mental disorders.But many of them do recover if they have the capacity
                to be honest.\n\nOur stories disclose in a general way what we use to be like, what happened, and what we are like now. If you have decided you want what we have and are willing to go
                to any lengths to get it - then you are ready to take certain steps.</string>
    <string name="reading2b">At some of these we balked. We thought we could find an easier, softer way. But we could not. With all the earnestness at our command, we beg of you to be fearless and thorough from the very start. Some of us have tried to hold on to our old ideas and the result was nil until we let go absolutely. Remember that we deal with alcohol - cunning, baffling, powerful! \n\nWithout help it is too much for us. But there is one who has all power - that One is God. May you find him now!\n\nHalf-measures availed us nothing. We stood at the turning point. We asked His protection and care with complete abandon.\n\nHere are the steps we took, which are suggested as a program of recovery.</string>
    <string name="reading2c">Many of us exclaimed“what an order! I can\'t go through with it.” \n\nDo not be discouraged. No one among us has been able to maintain anything like perfect adherence to these principles. We are not Saints. The point is, that we are willing to grow along spiritual lines. The principles we had set down are guides to progress. We claim spiritual progress rather than spiritual perfection.\n\nOur description of the alcoholic, the chapter to the agnostic, and our personal adventures before and after make clear three pertinent ideas:\n\na. That we were alcoholic and could not manage our own lives.\nb. That probably no human power could have relieved our alcoholism.\nc. That God could and would if he were sought.\n</string>

    <string name="reading3_title" >The 12 Steps</string>
    <string name="reading3">
        <b>1.</b> We admitted we were powerless over alcohol – that our lives had become unmanageable.\n\n
        2. Came to believe that a power greater than ourselves could restore us to sanity.\n\n
        3. Made a decision to turn our will and our lives over to the care of God - as we understood him.\n\n
        4. Made a searching and fearless moral inventory of ourselves.\n\n
        5. Admitted to God, to ourselves, and to another human being the exact nature of our wrongs.\n\n
        6. Were entirely ready to have God remove all these defects of character.\n\n
        7. Humbly asked him to remove our shortcomings.\n\n
        8. Made a list of all persons we had harmed, and became willing to make amends to them all.\n\n
        9. Made direct amends to such people wherever possible, except when to do so would injure them or others.\n\n
        10. Continued to take personal inventory and when we were wrong promptly admitted it.\n\n
        11. Sought through prayer and meditation to improve our conscious contact with God as we understood Him, praying only for knowledge of his will for us and the power to carry that out.\n\n
        12. Having had a spiritual awakening as a result of these steps, we tried to carry this message to alcoholics, and to practice these principals in all our affairs.</string>

    <string name="step_one"   >1. We admitted we were powerless over alcohol – that our lives had become unmanageable.</string>
    <string name="step_two"   >2. Came to believe that a power greater than ourselves could restore us to sanity.</string>
    <string name="step_three" >3. Made a decision to turn our will and our lives over to the care of God - as we understood him.</string>
    <string name="step_four"  >4. Made a searching and fearless moral inventory of ourselves.</string>
    <string name="step_five"  >5. Admitted to God, to ourselves, and to another human being the exact nature of our wrongs.</string>
    <string name="step_six"   >6. Were entirely ready to have God remove all these defects of character.</string>
    <string name="step_seven" >7. Humbly asked him to remove our shortcomings.</string>
    <string name="step_eight" >8. Made a list of all persons we had harmed, and became willing to make amends to them all.</string>
    <string name="step_nine"  >9. Made direct amends to such people wherever possible, except when to do so would injure them or others.</string>
    <string name="step_ten"   >10. Continued to take personal inventory and when we were wrong promptly admitted it.</string>
    <string name="step_eleven">11. Sought through prayer and meditation to improve our conscious contact with God as we understood Him, praying only for knowledge of his will for us and the power to carry that out.</string>
    <string name="step_twelve">12. Having had a spiritual awakening as a result of these steps, we tried to carry this message to alcoholics, and to practice these principals in all our affairs.</string>

    <string name="reading4_title" >The 12 Traditions</string>
    <string name="reading4">
        1. Our common welfare should come first; personal recovery depends upon A.A. unity.\n\n
        2. For our group purpose there is but one ultimate authority – a loving God as He may express Himself in our group conscience. Our leaders are but trusted servants, they do not govern.\n\n
        3. The only requirement for A.A. membership is a desire to stop drinking.\n\n
        4. Each group should be autonomous except in matters affecting other groups, or A.A. as a whole.\n\n
        5. Each group has but one primary purpose – to carry its message to the alcoholic who still suffers.\n\n
        6. An A.A. group ought never endorse, finance or lend the A.A. name to any related facility or outside enterprise, lest problems of money, property and prestige divert us from our primary purpose.\n\n
        7. Every A.A. group ought to be fully self-supporting, declining outside contributions.\n\n
        8. Alcoholics Anonymous should remain forever nonprofessional, but our service centres may employ special workers.\n\n
        9. A.A., as such, ought never be organized, but we may create service boards or committees directly responsible to those they serve.\n\n
        10. Alcoholics Anonymous has no opinion on outside issues, hence the A.A. name ought never be drawn into public controversy.\n\n
        11. Our public relations policy is based upon attraction rather than promotion; we need always maintain personal anonymity at the level of press, radio and films.\n\n
        12. Anonymity is the spiritual foundation of all our Traditions, ever reminding us to place principles before personalities.</string>

    <string name="trad_one"   >1. Our common welfare should come first; personal recovery depends upon A.A. unity.</string>
    <string name="trad_two"   >2. For our group purpose there is but one ultimate authority – a loving God as He may express Himself in our group conscience. Our leaders are but trusted servants, they do not govern.</string>
    <string name="trad_three" >3. The only requirement for A.A. membership is a desire to stop drinking.</string>
    <string name="trad_four"  >4. Each group should be autonomous except in matters affecting other groups, or A.A. as a whole.</string>
    <string name="trad_five"  >5. Each group has but one primary purpose – to carry its message to the alcoholic who still suffers.</string>
    <string name="trad_six"   >6. An A.A. group ought never endorse, finance or lend the A.A. name to any related facility or outside enterprise, lest problems of money, property and prestige divert us from our primary purpose.</string>
    <string name="trad_seven" >7. Every A.A. group ought to be fully self-supporting, declining outside contributions.</string>
    <string name="trad_eight" >8. Alcoholics Anonymous should remain forever nonprofessional, but our service centres may employ special workers.</string>
    <string name="trad_nine"  >9. A.A., as such, ought never be organized, but we may create service boards or committees directly responsible to those they serve.</string>
    <string name="trad_ten"   >10. Alcoholics Anonymous has no opinion on outside issues, hence the A.A. name ought never be drawn into public controversy.</string>
    <string name="trad_eleven">11. Our public relations policy is based upon attraction rather than promotion; we need always maintain personal anonymity at the level of press, radio and films.</string>
    <string name="trad_twelve">12. Anonymity is the spiritual foundation of all our Traditions, ever reminding us to place principles before personalities.</string>

    <string name="reading5_title">Responsibility Pledge</string>
    <string name="reading5">I am Responsible.\nWhen anyone, anywhere, reaches out for help, I want the hand of AA to always be there.\nAnd for that,I am Responsible.</string>

    <string name="reading6_title">The AA Promises</string>
    <string name="reading6_ref">Big Book p83–84</string>
    <string name="reading6">
        1. If we are painstaking about this phase of our development, we will be amazed before we are half way through.\n\n
        2. We are going to know a new freedom and a new happiness.\n\n
        3. We will not regret the past nor wish to shut the door on it.\n\n
        4. We will comprehend the word serenity and we will know peace.\n\n
        5. No matter how far down the scale we have gone, we will see how our experience can benefit others.\n\n
        6. That feeling of uselessness and self-pity will disappear.\n\n
        7. We will lose interest in selfish things and gain interest in our fellows.\n\n
        8. Self-seeking will slip away.\n\n
        9. Our whole attitude and outlook upon life will change.\n\n
        10. Fear of people and of economic insecurity will leave us.\n\n
        11. We will intuitively know how to handle situations which used to baffle us.\n\n
        12. We will suddenly realize that God is doing for us what we could not do for ourselves\n\n
        Are these extravagant promises? We think not. They are being fulfilled among us - sometimes quickly, sometimes slowly. They will always materialize if we work for them.</string>

    <string name="prayer1_title">The Serenity Prayer</string>
    <string name="prayer1">God, grant me the SERENITY to accept the things I cannot change, COURAGE to change the things I can, and WISDOM to know the difference.</string>
    <string name="prayer1_auth">Reinhold Niebuhr (1892–1971)</string>

    <string name="prayer2_title">The Lord\'s Prayer</string>
    <string name="prayer2">Our Father,\nwho art in heaven,\nHallowed be thy Name.\nThy Kingdom come,\nThy will be done,\nOn earth as it is in heaven.\n\nGive us this day our daily bread.\nAnd forgive us our trespasses.\nAs we forgive those who trespass against us.\nAnd lead us not into temptation,\nBut deliver us from evil.\n\nFor Thine is the Kingdom,\nthe Power and the Glory,\nFor ever and ever,\nAmen</string>

    <string name="prayer3_title">Prayer of St. Francis</string>
    <string name="prayer3">
        Lord, make me an instrument of your peace.
        \nWhere there is hatred,\n\tlet me bring love.
        \nWhere there is offense,\n\tlet me bring pardon.
        \nWhere there is discord,\n\tlet me bring union.
        \nWhere there is error,\n\tlet me bring truth.
        \nWhere there is doubt,\n\tlet me bring faith.
        \nWhere there is despair,\n\tlet me bring hope.
        \nWhere there is darkness,\n\tlet me bring your light.
        \nWhere there is sadness,\n\tlet me bring joy.
        \n\nO Master, let me not seek as much to be consoled as to console, to be understood as to understand,to be loved as to love.
        \n\nFor it is in giving that one receives, it is in self-forgetting that one finds, it is in pardoning that one is pardoned, it is in dying that one is raised to eternal life.</string>
    <string name="prayer3_auth">x</string>

    <string name="prayer4_title">x</string>
    <string name="prayer4">x</string>
    <string name="prayer4_auth">x</string>

    <string name="prayer5_title">x</string>
    <string name="prayer5">x</string>
    <string name="prayer5_auth">x</string>

</resources>